# Mahamudul Hasan Mithhu

+(880) 1742001078 • mithhu333@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/mithhu • github.com/mithhu

### **Software Engineer**

A Software Engineer with around 2 years of professional experience who came from an Electrical and Electronics Engineering background and also graduated with a diploma in Web Development which was achieved with a full scholarship by Facebook.

### **Professional Experiences**

### **Software Engineer, Evaly**

June 2020 - Present

- Accomplished a faster response time of client sites by caching and prefetching data using React Query which also made sites more interactive and user friendly. <u>Website</u>
- Migrated sites to TypeScript and followed best practices of coding.
- Created analytics dashboard for admin sites using React Chart and D3.

#### **Junior Software Engineer, TiGrow Ltd**

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

- Helped to design architecture using React, Redux, React Router and TypeScript.
- Developed a Trello-like task management system with basic features of social network.

#### Front-end Developer (Intern), Circle Fintech Ltd

March 2019 - July 2019

• Built the Front-end part of a payment gateway system to make it possible to do payment from any local digital payment service.

## **Personal Projects**

**MusicTube:** A FullStack app that has all the core features of YouTube-like video upload, watch, like, dislike, authentication etc. This site was built using React, Node, Express and PostgreSQL and deployed in Heroku. Website

**Chip-8 Virtual Machine:** Built a Chip-8 virtual machine from scratch in vanilla JS. This site was developed using Canvas Element and Web Audio API. Website

**Cat Fight:** Built a turn-based game in which two players can fight against each other. The game was developed using object-oriented vanilla JavaScript. Website

#### **Technical Skills**

- Front-end: JavaScript (ES6), React, TypeScript, Redux, React Query, React Router, Next, D3, CSS3, HTML5
- Backend: Python, Webpack, SQL, C++, Node, Express, Object Oriented Programming

#### Education